hundreds of thousands of dollars even
millions of dollars with just a couple
of hours a day sometimes even minutes
this is what day trading allows you to
do you can open and close the operation
with one single day that's why it's
called day trading and depending on your
experience the way you approach your
strategy and your risk management you
can have results like these or even like
these and day trading is one of the most
common trading Styles in the market and
in this video I'm going to reveal to you
the tips and wisdom that I wish I knew
when I started day trading because it
would have saved me a lot lot of time so
first things first you have to
understand what is day trading actually
and it's simply a way of how you can
trade in the markets and it's pretty
self-explanatory day trading equals
trading every day your Trad usually last
for a period of 18 to 24 hours so what
if the trade goes over the 24 hours well
it's no longer a day trade now it's
called an interday trade but it's not a
big deal if it goes over a couple of
hours and if it goes over then 24 Hours
by 2 3 days now you've entered a swing
trade swing trades usually go over a
couple of days or over a week if you
guys want to know more about swing
trading check this video out right here
which explains it to the te and there's
many other types of trading there's
scalping which is on the lower time
frames which you're trading either a
couple of minutes or maybe an hour a day
and then there's position siiz trading
which you're taking a trade for more
than 1 to two months and that is the
most simplest way to understand the
different types of trading it could be
very confusing at the beginning because
it looks like there's so much going on
but it's very simple there's four types
of trading scalping very lower time
frames day trading which you're trading
to the day intraday trading which you're
Trading a little bit more than a day and
then you have swing trading which you're
trading for a little bit over a week and
then position trading but that's
something that you do for long-term
Investments but in this video we're
going to only be focusing on day trading
and I want you to know why because we're
going to focus on all of the advantages
which there is many and we're also going
to focus on the disadvantages because
there is many and I wish I knew these
when I started trading as well so to
start off these are the advantages first
off their trades are extremely fast you
can enter a position in the market
immediately let's say you want to buy
euro USD right now now the moment you
click buy you're in the market and
usually trades don't last more than a
day so you have your results whether you
win or lose by the end of that day so it
helps you with your patience and the
second Point funny enough it's actually
patience so it's a double-edged sword it
can actually work for the benefit of you
because let's say you're busy throughout
the week let's say you work two three
days out of the week you don't have to
trade those two three days you only day
trade the two three days you're free so
it's good because you could be patient
and not trade the days you're at work
and you can still have opportunities but
it can also be a double-edged sword
because if you're not patience and you
take too many day trades you can over
trade and actually blow your account and
lose a lot of money so that's a
disadvantage but we're going to get to
those very soon the next point is you
can literally access trading anywhere in
the world whether you're in America
Latin America South Africa London
Australia Russia China anywhere where
there is simply Wi-Fi and a laptop you
are able to actually day trade you don't
need a license to day trade you simply
just open up your account deposit your
money apply your strategy and that's it
you don't need a license you don't have
to go to school all you need is a
profitable strategy you can get a solid
opportunity every day or every other day
meaning you can literally make money in
the markets every single day that the
Market's open with Forex it is open
Monday through Friday technically
obviously with the exception of Sunday
but we don't trade Sundays and it's open
245 every single day out of the week
every hour out of the day another great
benefit is that there is a load of day
traders in this community and it's a
great Advantage because you can meet
other like-minded people but it can also
be a double-edged sword because you
don't know who to listen to and it can
almost be information overload and you
can get lost and confused but again more
of that once we get to the disadvantages
to add you don't have to be in front of
the charts every single hour of the day
let's say you're only day trading the
New York session you only have to be
there for four to 5 hours Max and that's
it you can enjoy the rest of the day or
let's say you're trading London session
you only have to be there for the four
to five 6 hours of the session and
that's it you can enjoy the rest of your
day so the benefit is that you don't
have to be in front of the charts for
every sing single tick of the
Candlestick that leads me to to my next
point which is literally once you catch
a trade you're done you can literally go
enjoy your day and you don't have to be
stuck in front of the screens like let's
say a scalper or an Inay Trader which is
more focused on every single tick of the
market for the most part risk to reward
ratio is amazing because when you're a
day trader you're not catching a one to
one you're catching a minimum of a one
to2 risk reward now don't get confused
with that this is your first time
hearing it we're going to talk a little
bit about that later in this video as
well because the risk to reward is
actually what led me to become
profitable if I didn't have a positive
risk orward ratio I wouldn't be in the
position where I'm today and I'm going
to explain to you how key that is so you
can become successful with trading and I
think one of the main benefits about day
trading is that you realistically only
have to take one or two day trades a
week and that's it you don't have to
trade anymore for the week so actually
less is better yes you're a day trader
you can have many opportunities but you
don't have to take all of them you could
only take the best ones so those were
some of the advantages and there is many
more out there but let's get into the
disadvantages which there are actually
some things that can sneak up on you if
I wouldn't have told you this inside
this video I would have been a very very
expensive lesson a big disadvantage is
that the market as a day trader
sometimes is choppy and since you're a
day trader you want to trade every
single day so this can cause you to be
doubtful of your strategy due to the
market being irrational or just not
following the trend overall because
let's say for example that the market at
the end of the week ends up moving up 4
500 Pips but let's say it was choppy for
2 3 days this would have messed up your
day trading strategy another bad point
is that since you're a day trader and
you access so many trades once you enter
a losing streak of let's say five or six
more trades you are now in a downward
spiral of losses until you pretty much
blow your account because since you're a
day trader you have access to so many
opportunities sometimes you can't
differentiate the good opportunities
from the bad ones and that also leads me
to the next point which is having too
many opportunities is actually a bad
thing because you can overtrade and you
can become overwhelmed with how many
opportunities the market is giving you
so you actually have to be very careful
when looking at the charts the day trade
because if you taking trades every
single day because you call yourself a
day trader you're now forcing yourself
into positions that probably wouldn't
make sense for a real day trader the
double-edged sword that I was talking
about that there's a lot of day Traders
and it's a good thing because you can
meet a lot of like-minded people well
the bad side about the sword is that
there's a lot of fake gurus out there
there's a lot of people that they don't
know what they're talking about at all
people that literally has started
trading for 3 months and they think they
know more than everybody just because
they figured out how to use these
trading platforms so it's actually a
disadvantage that there's a lot of day
Traders because if you don't only focus
on one mentor and one Trader you can get
all of this outside noise and it could
completely throw you off your tracks and
it can be devastating because you don't
know who to listen there's so many
successful day Traders and you don't
know who to listen to so it's a big
disadvantage but that one's easy to
block out because you just focus on one
mentor and that's it and another crazy
disadvantage which some of you guys
would maybe want to have is that you can
make a ton of money super fast and
this is actually not a good thing
because if you make a ton of money
super fast you've never made this money
before you don't know how to handle it
you don't know what it would do with it
let's say you've never made $10,000 in
one month and you make that now in one
single day trade I bet you're going to
feel amazing you're going to feel like
the king of the world but now your
emotions are tied to the money because
since you've never made it now you're
going to do things you have never done
and as soon as you spend the money you
can never make it again because you
think you're the king of the world when
you have barely just figured out this
day trading so making a lot of money
fast is actually a bad thing but it's an
opportunity that the market has for you
there every single day so those are some
of the disadvantages but if you actually
want to start making those $10,000 a day
you have to have a real account right
you can't make money on demo demo is
also known as paper trading which is
fake trading this is because you are
able to see the market conditions that
the broker gives you you're able to test
out your strategy in demo money but
there's also so the real account where
you actually have to deposit and every
single trade that you take goes live
into the market the demo trades also go
executed straight into the market but
they're never going to be exactly the
same as the live markets because there's
obviously slippage and all that stuff so
if you want to know more about this real
account and demo account and how you
create one just watch this video right
here because it explains it to the team
it is very key that you know when is the
right time to deposit into your real
account and how long you should actually
trade in your demo account but I can
summarize it for you a demo account is
fake money it's demo you you can
literally put as much money as you want
you can become a millionaire in demo you
can just deposit as much demo money as
you want and you can trade it you can
try your strategy you can try your take
profit your entries your stop loss
everything just so you get comfortable
with the markets and you get comfortable
with your strategy now once you do that
school when now you have to be ready to
deposit money into your account so now
once you deposit the money into your
account you deposit into the broker you
connect it to the trading platform and
then you are executing into the market
live which this is going to lead me to
my next point which is what platforms
should you use and I only recommend two
platforms and now there is hundreds of
platforms out there they're very
confusing some are very tacky some are
very old some are even too advanced and
it's just information overload I use the
most common and the most used in this
industry and they've been around for 20
to 25 years plus so the main platform
you need is trading view trading view is
going to be the platform where you can
actually analyze your markets this is
where you're going to be able to line up
your charts this where you're going to
be able to put your areas of interest is
where you're going to be able to
actually analyze the markets to identify
whether you want to buy or if you want
to then sell this is what I've been
using since day one this is what every
single Trader influencer has been using
since day one as well but could get
confusing because if somebody doesn't
tell you that this is the platform right
off the bat it can get confusing because
there is a lot of other platforms out
there that try and be like trading View
and then the next one is metat Trader 4
or metat Trader 5 this is where you're
actually going to execute the trades now
just because you analyzed on trading
view that means you actually have to
click buy or sell you can't click Buy
buy or sell on trading view you can
click buy or sell on metatrader that's
where the money is going to go you're
going to deposit your money into metat
Trader 4 metat Trader 5 technically into
the broker but then the broker connects
to metat Trader 4 and metat Trader 5 and
I have a video that explains both of
these platforms to Perfection right here
so if you want to know more about these
two platforms make sure you check out
this video because I go into great
detail how you can create an account how
you deposit the money I even take a
trade live with you guys in this video
right here so if you want to know more
about it just click on that video but to
summarize very briefly Trading is where
you analyze your trades and then metat
Trader 4 and metat Trader 5 is where you
actually execute the trades without
trading view you can't analyze the
markets without metat Trader 4 or metat
Trader 5 you cannot execute in the
actual markets and both of these are in
the app store they are free apps they
don't cost you anything I've had them on
my phone since day one and I actually
have my own section on my phone with it
CU it's my trading section and I don't
focus on anything else that is not those
two apps trading View and metat Trader
so now that you know that you need a
real account or a demo account and then
you need to analyze the charts on
trading view or execute the trade on
metat Trader 4 metat Trader 5 now you
need the actual strategy you need to
have the skill set to actually be able
to execute these trades and make money
we're out here to make money let's be
honest so this is what matters the
actual strategy now you have the
platforms now we're moving into the
actual skill set that it requires to
make money in these markets and the key
is to have a strategy that works I'm a
big believer on don't fix something
that's not broken if you see people out
there that have strategies that work you
see the track record you see them making
profits time and time again strategy
probably works just go and copy it it's
the easiest thing you could ever do I
wish I learned that at the beginning
because I wasted so much time trying to
develop my own strategy I didn't want to
drop my ego and I didn't want to learn
from somebody else because I thought I
could do this all on my own and I spent
thousands of dollars on just back
testing thousands of hours I'm just
trying to see if this works on the back
testing end of the market and on the
live testing of the market so I would
have saved so much time if I would just
put my ego and pride to the side and
just learned from somebody not try and
make my own strategy I didn't come into
this Market knowing anything so why did
I think I can make something out of
nothing just get a strategy that is
tested and that is proven and once you
have that it's going to be so much
easier to make money in the market
you're going to like you're literally
going to short in the learning curb by
by I even think years because you're
just removing all the noise and you're
only focusing on what matters and by
learning from somebody you're literally
saving hours of testing this strategy
and actually seeing if it works this
person is literally showing you it works
so you just learn from them I think it's
the easiest route to take and the moment
I did that is when my trading completely
turned 180° so now that you have the
profitable strategy you need to have
this next Point without this next point
you can throw everything out the window
you can throw the real account you can
throw the trading platforms you can even
throw the strategy out the window
without this next point that I'm going
to tell you you will simply not be
successful in trading and that is going
to be risk management the way you manage
your assets is going to Define how
you're going to grow in trading as
simple as it is if you treat your
account with little to no respect and
you have no risk management that's how
the markets are going to treat you with
little to no respect and you're not
going to have any results you need to
have a bulletproof risk management plan
when executing every single trade this
way you know exactly how much you're
going to lose how much you're going to
gain and what is the probability of you
actually gaining versus losing let's say
over the course of 10 to 20 traits this
is where you create your win rate and
your risk to reward rate remember that
risk to reward will we talked at the
beginning of the video this is exactly
what it's going to fall in place right
now this is going to be part of your
risk management keep in mind without
risk management this is simply not going
to work you can get off this video and
I'm just going to save you the time
because the next points that I'm going
to explain are going to tie everything
together and lead you to success but you
can't tie everything together without
this risk management key and let me give
you the example that I use every single
month that I start trading literally the
first of every single month I pick a
certain percentage that I'm going to
risk on my account and I stick to that
percentage throughout the whole entire
month I'm not changing how much I'm
going to risk on a trade on Monday
versus then on Tuesday it's a different
percentage and then on Friday it's a
different percentage there's no
sustainability in that no investors
going to look at you and be like yeah
this guy has a solid risk management
plan it all makes sense no he wants to
see consistency he wants to see
consistent results in the same thing
over and over and over again the only
way you can do that is by having a
bulletproof risk management strategy so
what I do is I pick a percentage at the
beginning of the month and I stick
through it through the whole entire
month it doesn't matter if I won five
trades in a row doesn't matter if I lost
10 trades in a row I'm going to use the
same exact risk management percentage of
the account every single time
and I can't emphasize how powerful this
will be to determine whether you're
going to be profitable or not and
there's months where I know to risk a
little bit more percentages and there's
months where I know to risk a little bit
less percentages this is due to my
experience in the markets simply because
the market moves and cycles and I see
the same things happen over and over and
over again in certain months and in
certain quarters of the year so now that
you tie this risk management together
now you need to combine your strategy
with your risk management to not your
trading plan now a strategy is just what
you need in order to actually enter a
trade risk management is where you're
going to risk a trade but then the
trading plan is all of this combined
together meaning that you cannot take a
trade unless everything in your trading
plan is checked out now this can mean
whether you have a trade in early Monday
morning whether it is only a certain
pair only at a certain session you need
to have a certain entry signal your
trading plan is going to be the strict
plan that you need to follow every
single time with my students the trading
plan literally has a checklist and if
you don't check off every single thing
on the checklist you don't take the
trade why are you going to take a trade
on something that doesn't have every
single box checked off would you risk
money on something that you don't have
certainty over there's no reason the
market is not going to go anywhere
there's endless opportunity so we only
take trades that every single box is
ticked off now there's some days where
no not everything gets ticked off so we
don't trade but there's some weeks where
we get three four five trades ticked off
every other day and this is the key you
need to have the trading planning you
need to wait for every single trade to
take off every single box inside your
trading plan and to give you a brief
sneak peek into my trading plan I 100%
will not even look at a pair unless it
has these three things the first thing
is we need to have two time frames in
sync whether it is the weekly or the
daily or the daily and the full hour not
any time frames any lower I'm only
sticking to those three to understand
the direction of the market so I don't
look at a trade unless we have the two
time frames in sync next is we need to
be at a daily or weekly area of interest
if we're not at a daily or weekly area
of interest I'm simply not looking at
the trade and then third I need to have
my actual set and forget strategy to
apply at that area of Interest once a
pair has all of that now is when I bring
out my actual checklist and I start
checking things off but until I don't
have those three things which is part of
my checklist I'm simply not looking at
the pair and I can express how important
this is like everything that I'm
explaining to you right now it's like an
engine of a vehicle the engine of the
vehicle has so many components you have
the engine the transmission the Pistons
the oil the wheels the cluster the
electronics the car can't function
without all of these things the car can
look okay but it won't function it won't
get you anywhere unless it has
everything pieced together this is
exactly the same this is like an engine
of a vehicle you need to have all of
these components working together in
order so you can successfully drive the
car and be safe and it be something
sustainable and that last a long time
now yes you can get a car you can put a
little bit of gas you can put whatever
coolant you can tie the tire with only
one lug nut but that's not sustainable
that's not going to last a long time
it's going to get to the point where
it's going to break down and it won't
work again it's the same thing with
trading you can have a trading plan that
you don't have everything there and it
might work one or two or maybe three
trades but over the course of 5 to 10
years which is how long we plan to trade
which is forever it's not going to be
sustainable you need to have a perfectly
built engine so everything is
sustainable and everything everything
works in sync together and that is
something that I wish I learned at the
beginning but luckily I figured it out
and I have a bulletproof system I have
my engine built perfectly that it runs
automatically without me having to worry
I know exactly what I'm looking for
every single time when I enter a trade
and once you have all that together then
comes one of the most sneak attacks that
there is that is the psychology of
trading the psychology of trading is
almost like preparing yourself for the
traffic that you're going to have in
this car you can have a beautiful
vehicle you can have a rolls roids like
the one that I have it run perfectly but
when you go out to drive it the roads
are all messed up there's traffic
everywhere it's raining and it just
annoys you because you want to enjoy the
car it's the same exact thing with the
strategy you can have the best strategy
out there you can have your checklist
ready to go you can have all of the all
of the boxes with your pen ready to go
and the markets the trading view the
live you going to have everything ready
to go but your emotions get to you and
what does that happen you either get
greedy you get fear of missing out you
get anxious you get impatient and all of
that goes out the window simply because
of your emotions so you can have the
best car out there but because you
weren't prepared to have the actual
driver experience of living in Miami you
don't end up enjoying the car because
you're focus on everything else out
there it's the same thing with the
strategy you can have the best strategy
but until your mind isn't ready to be
prepared to handle all of those emotions
it simply won't matter and I wish I knew
this at the beginning because I would
have realized that the problem wasn't
the strategy and I would have realized
the problem was actually me and that's
going to lead me to my Kaizen Point
Kaizen had one of the best attitudes and
this refers to always having a Pro
Advanced attitude you don't have to
improve 100% every single week literally
it's pretty much impossible all you have
to do is improve 1% a day and at that
that is still a lot because if you do it
over the course of the year that is
obviously a 3 165% Improvement you're at
three times of the person that you were
when you got started in one second
single year you have to remember that a
Rolls-Royce takes 6 months to build
versus a Toyota Corolla I think it takes
like 48 hours or 72 hours Rome wasn't
built in a day good thing takes time and
if you're going to make money from the
markets forever it's going to take time
for you to perfect who you are as a
Trader and these are just some of the
small day trading tips that I wish I
knew when I started trading I put it all
inside this video here for you guys
because these tips are what led me to
Now teach thousands of traders to
generate anywhere from a th000 to $1,500
a week as a beginner set and forget
Trader using my set and forget strategy
I've literally gotten students from
making nothing to now making anywhere
from
$1,500 every single week using my set
and forget strategy if you want to know
more about the set and forget strategy
and actually what it consists about and
what does it even set and forget mean
just hit the link in the description
below and it's going to make extreme
sense because I've gotten traders that
were working full-time jobs at the mall
or super corporate jobs to now becoming
a full-time day trader swing Trader so
if you want to know more about the
center for strategy who I am and how I
change these people's lives just click
the link in the description below I have
a video there for you that is going to
explain everything and great detail so I
appreciate you guys watching all this
video to the end make sure you hit that
like And subscribe button and I'll see
you guys in the next video